<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on Jeremy Hager</title><link>https://yugawa.io/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on Jeremy Hager</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://yugawa.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting a Windows VM to work with libvirt</title><link>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-05-windows-vm-with-libvirt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-05-windows-vm-with-libvirt/</guid><description>So on my last entry I mentioned trying to get Windows Server 2016 to work on libvirt.
After I tried installing the GUI to connect via VNC somewhere along the way I reconnected to ssh, and sure enough a little message popped up: Web console: https://centos8.lan:9090/ or https://192.168.86.41:9090/. I thought this a bit odd, then tested out to see if my suspicions were correct - could I use the web console to view the GUI on my Windows Server 2016 VM?</description></item><item><title>Installing a "headless" CentOS 7 VM</title><link>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-11-headless-centos7-vm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-11-headless-centos7-vm/</guid><description>I found a section in the Unix and Linux Sysadmin Handbook about kickstart files - something I crossed by earlier when I was trying to get CentOS 7 to work on my homebuilt computer. However I was going through the book page-by-page at the time, and like I mentioned I felt like I was spending too much time on getting CentOS 7 to work on my homebuilt hardware.
An interesting error I kept running into when I first was trying to get the VM to work was ERROR Kernel arguments are only supported with location or kernel installs.</description></item><item><title>Lazy logging/blogging</title><link>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-03-lazy-logging-blogging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-03-lazy-logging-blogging/</guid><description>For now, just going to keep updating the README.md so I can keep a short list of interesting things I find on the internet that&amp;rsquo;s helpful. Like a favorites bar but public.
Currently trying to learn more about Linux and going through UNIX and Linux System Administration Handbook, 5thEdition, while following a Reddit post about how to learn Enterprise Linux basics. You can find this by IConrad here (archive, in case it ever gets removed).</description></item></channel></rss>