<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Jeremy Hager</title><link>https://yugawa.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Jeremy Hager</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 15:20:11 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yugawa.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Powerbook 140 Pi - Part 1</title><link>https://yugawa.io/posts/2021-12-31-powerbook-140-pi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 15:20:11 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://yugawa.io/posts/2021-12-31-powerbook-140-pi/</guid><description>I was watching Bill Nye The Science Guy one day, and noticed something interesting: he started talking about the Nobel Prize, and was using a cool retro notebook! I had to pause it and take another look:
Then I thought hey, what if I repurposed one of these?. Thus I fell down the rabbit hole of trying to figure out what macintosh he had (probably some sort of powerbook, as the episode came out in 1993 and filming would have been done within a year so maybe powerbook in 1992?</description></item><item><title>New Webiste</title><link>https://yugawa.io/posts/2021-12-04-new-webiste/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 22:04:19 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://yugawa.io/posts/2021-12-04-new-webiste/</guid><description>Making a new website. I saw someone else had a similar website and really dig the way this one looks. Hopefully good things will come soon. I got the idea when reading https://filipnikolovski.com/posts/thoughts-on-microservices. Toyed around with the css a little, trying to remove the margins and have everything left-aligned. I realized it was a little hard to read, so leaving default for now.
More to come in the coming months.</description></item><item><title>Getting a Windows VM to work with libvirt</title><link>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-05-windows-vm-with-libvirt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-05-windows-vm-with-libvirt/</guid><description>So on my last entry I mentioned trying to get Windows Server 2016 to work on libvirt.
After I tried installing the GUI to connect via VNC somewhere along the way I reconnected to ssh, and sure enough a little message popped up: Web console: https://centos8.lan:9090/ or https://192.168.86.41:9090/. I thought this a bit odd, then tested out to see if my suspicions were correct - could I use the web console to view the GUI on my Windows Server 2016 VM?</description></item><item><title>Got a new website up and running!</title><link>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-16-new-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-16-new-website/</guid><description>Hello! This is my first blog post on my new website. Feel free to have a look around, though it may feel a bit empty for now.
Last time I updated, I was trying to get moinmoin to work. As I began to try to get it to work I would was having a difficult time understanding the best way to use it, as well as getting it to work on its own vs.</description></item><item><title>Installing a "headless" CentOS 7 VM</title><link>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-11-headless-centos7-vm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-11-headless-centos7-vm/</guid><description>I found a section in the Unix and Linux Sysadmin Handbook about kickstart files - something I crossed by earlier when I was trying to get CentOS 7 to work on my homebuilt computer. However I was going through the book page-by-page at the time, and like I mentioned I felt like I was spending too much time on getting CentOS 7 to work on my homebuilt hardware.
An interesting error I kept running into when I first was trying to get the VM to work was ERROR Kernel arguments are only supported with location or kernel installs.</description></item><item><title>Lazy logging/blogging</title><link>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-03-lazy-logging-blogging/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-03-lazy-logging-blogging/</guid><description>For now, just going to keep updating the README.md so I can keep a short list of interesting things I find on the internet that&amp;rsquo;s helpful. Like a favorites bar but public.
Currently trying to learn more about Linux and going through UNIX and Linux System Administration Handbook, 5thEdition, while following a Reddit post about how to learn Enterprise Linux basics. You can find this by IConrad here (archive, in case it ever gets removed).</description></item><item><title>Moving on with Foreman</title><link>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-09-01-moving-on-with-forman/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-09-01-moving-on-with-forman/</guid><description>Foreman has been giving me a little trouble as I began to set it up. First thing that happened is I could not import errata correctly, and I tried 2 different scripts out there to accomplish it. After several re-tries, I figured a fresh start would be good and reverted the Foreman VM back to before all of these changes happened.
Well after going through the process again, I unfortunately ran into another issue: I tried to back up the server.</description></item><item><title>Moving to containers</title><link>https://yugawa.io/posts/2021-1-16-moving-to-containers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yugawa.io/posts/2021-1-16-moving-to-containers/</guid><description>Going to keep this short - It&amp;rsquo;s time to move from classic VMs to containers.
Currently I have several VMs that are hosted from my home server. However what I really want to learn is not only nix administration but also cloud technologies and IaC. I still plan to try to follow the sysadmin guide, but from here on out going to try to set all future infrastructure under Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>New milestone and setting up networks</title><link>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-10-7-new-milestone-and-setting-up-networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-10-7-new-milestone-and-setting-up-networks/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy! I created a new vm, dns-dhcp which will serve my dns and dhcp for the internal.virtnet environment. I configured dhcp to only hand out addresses to libvirt vms (they all start with 52:54:00), I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a few hours a day trying to find out why pxe boot wasn&amp;rsquo;t working on libvirt, and finally realized I had to create a new network for my environment.
This post will be a bit longer than my typical blog posts, as it is a culmination of the last few weeks.</description></item><item><title>Polishing the website</title><link>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-24-polishing-the-website/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://yugawa.io/posts/2020-08-24-polishing-the-website/</guid><description>The website is almost finished! I feel I can start focusing on Linux again. I also read about RedHat Developer Subscription, which allows you to use RedHat for free, with some limitations of course.
I think I&amp;rsquo;ll continue using CentOS for now though. My thoughts are that forcing myself to learn the free and open versions of everything will help my understanding of how each component and package works with each other.</description></item></channel></rss>